mktginc.com 2016-02-15

# Mktg, Inc. Privacy Policy

Mktg, Inc. Privacy Policy
1. Description
   Mktg, Inc. (Question: Is this the proper legal definition?) ("Mktg" and any reference
   to Mktg shall include Mktg’s affiliates, subsidiaries and divisions, including, without
   limitation SampleSolutions, its affiliates, subsidiaries and divisions) is a market
   research and consulting company providing information that helps its clients
   understand the needs and preferences of their customers. Mktg’s headquarters and
   principal place of business is at 200 Carleton Avenue, East Islip, NY 11730.
2. Privacy Commitment
   Mktg is firmly committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (this
   “Privacy Policy”) applies to all Personal Information submitted to Mktg. Personal
   Information (“Personal Information”) means any information identifiable with you,
   including, without limitation, first and last name, residential address, email address,
   telephone number(s) (home and/or cell), and date of birth. Mktg strives to conform
   its privacy practices with applicable international, national, Federal, state and/or
   local laws, codes, and regulations; and the industry codes, standards, rules, and
   regulations of various market and opinion research professional associations,
   including, without limitation, the ICC/ESOMAR International Code on Market and
   Social Research and the Code of Standards and Ethics for Survey Research of the
   Council of American Survey Research Organizations, with whom Mktg is a member.
   Participation in any survey offered (individually at “Survey” and collectively
   “Surveys”), provided, hosted, or administered by Mktg is completely voluntary.
3. Security
   Mktg is committed to protecting the security and integrity of Personal Information.
   Mktg maintains commercially reasonable technical, administrative and physical
   safeguards to protect and secure Personal Information from unauthorized disclosure
   to, and/or use and/or access by, any third party or third parties. Mktg shall use,
   disclose, protect, secure and maintain all Personal Information submitted or
   provided to Mktg in accordance with any and all applicable international, Federal,
   state and/or local laws, codes, regulations, and requirements.
4. Surveys and Information Collected
   Mktg may invite you to participate in online Surveys. The information requested in
   these Surveys may include, but is not limited to, your opinions, purchase history, and
   purchase intent regarding consumer and/or business products and services. These
   Surveys may also request information defined as sensitive (e.g. data directly or
   indirectly revealing racial and ethnic origins, political, philosophical or religious

   opinions, trade union affiliation, health or sexual life). Again, you are not required to
   provide us with this information if you do not want to and failing to provide this
   information will not preclude you from participating. The information collected by
   these Surveys is used in connection with Mktg market research sponsored by third-
   party companies . We reserve the right to share this information in an anonymous
   singular summary and aggregate form with third parties for this purpose.
5. Mktg Use of Cookies
   a. Mktg Cookies. Cookies are small text files or other forms of data which are
       stored on a computer by a website that assigns a numerical user ID and stores
       certain information about the Internet browsing activity of the user of a
       computer or device. Mktg uses session and persistent cookies to make it easier
       for you to navigate the Mktg Website. Session cookies expire when you close
       your browser. Persistent cookies remain on your computer, indefinitely, until
       deleted. Personal Information is not stored or collected in the cookies used by
       Mktg. You may disable and/or delete cookies via your browser and/or plug-in
       settings; however, this may: (1) decrease the functionality of the Mktg Website;
       and (2) limit your ability to use and view the Mktg Website.
   b. Third Party Cookies. The use of cookies by Mktg’s affiliates, partners,
       Subcontractors (individually a “Subcontractor,” collectively “Subcontractors”),
       and/or clients is not covered by this Privacy Policy. Mktg does not have control
       over the policies and practices of such parties.
   c. Log Files. Mktg Websites automatically gathers certain information and stores
       this information in log files. This gathered information includes data available
       from a user’s web browser, including, without limitation, IP Address, browser
       type, Internet service provider, referring/exiting pages, operating system,
       date/time stamp, and click stream data.
6. Digital Fingerprinting; Data Validation
   a. Digital Fingerprinting. In general, digital fingerprinting technologies assign a
       unique identifier to a user’s computer or device to identify and track the
       computer or device. Mktg uses digital fingerprinting technology (the
       “Technology”) to assist Mktg’s clients in ensuring the integrity of Survey results
       by identifying duplicate and fraudulent respondents. The Technology analyzes
       publicly available information and data obtained from a computer or device’s
       web browser and from other publicly available data points, including, without
       limitation, the technical settings of the computer or device, the characteristics of
       the computer or device, and the computer or device’s IP Address, to create a
       unique identifier assigned to the computer or device. The unique identifier does
       not contain any information or data that individually identifies the person who is
       assigned the unique identifier. In furtherance of Mktg’s efforts to assist its
       clients in protecting and ensuring the integrity of Survey results, Mktg: (i) may

        link or associate your unique identifier to you and any of your Personal
        Information; (ii) may share your unique identifier with Mktg’s clients and with
        sample or panel providers; and (iii) may receive or obtain a unique identifier
        linked to you from a third party, including, without limitation, a sample or panel
        provider or a client of Mktg. Any unique identifier(s) received or obtained by
        Mktg and linked to an identified or identifiable individual shall be protected in
        accordance with this Privacy Policy.
        Mktg uses reasonable efforts to ensure that the Technology is safe, secure, and
        does not cause undue privacy or data security risks. Mktg uses and distributes
        the Technology in a professional and ethical manner and in accordance with: (i)
        this Privacy Policy and (ii) applicable laws and codes.
        If Mktg discovers or learns of any illegal or unethical conduct in connection with
        the use of the Technology, or that the Technology is being used in a manner
        inconsistent with the statements and/or disclosures made by Mktg. Mktg shall
        use reasonable efforts to restrict, limit, or prohibit the illegal or unethical
        conduct and to ensure the proper use and administration of the Technology.
    b. Data Validation. From time-to-time, Mktg may engage a third party or third
        parties to validate data. The purpose of the data validation is to assist Mktg’s
        clients in ensuring the integrity of Survey results. The data validation process
        involves: (i) Mktg disclosing or transferring Personal Information to a
        Subcontractor, (ii) the Subcontractor performing validation services, and (iii) the
        Subcontractor returning the Personal Information to Mktg with any updates or
        corrections and, if applicable, with a validation score. Mktg reserves the right to
        deny or reject Survey participation, if data is not validated to Mktg’s satisfaction.
7. Collection of Facebook ‘Likes’ Data
For some Surveys we collect Facebook ‘Likes’ to allow for more insight into the
preferences of our target audience. Accordingly, we may ask you to provide access to
your Facebook profile so we can read your Facebook ‘Likes.’ Providing access to your
Facebook ‘Likes’ is optional and not required to complete the Survey.
We will strip all Personal Information from your ‘Likes’ so that the resulting data is
completely anonymous. We will never discriminate or disqualify you from survey
participation based on your ‘Likes.’ Finally, we will not store your login information and;
therefore, we will not be able to view your profile after the Survey is complete.
8. Children’s Privacy Protection
Mktg strongly believes it is important to protect the online privacy of children.
Accordingly, Mktg adheres to applicable laws and codes pertaining to the protection of

children’s privacy, including, without limitation, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection
Act (US).
In the US, Mktg does not knowingly collect or receive Personal Information from an
individual under the age of thirteen (13), without prior parental consent. Outside of the
US, Mktg does not knowingly collect or receive Personal Information from an individual
under the age of fourteen (14), without prior parental consent. Children under the age
thresholds set forth above, are contacted to participate in Surveys through their parents
or guardians. For Surveys involving data subjects between the age thresholds listed
above and the age of seventeen (17), Mktg carefully considers both privacy issues and
parental concerns. Parents and guardians are encouraged to contact Mktg about this
Privacy Policy and to discuss their rights to access, edit, or delete Personal Information
of or about their child or children.
9. Third Party Links
Mktg may provide you with the ability to voluntarily link or connect to websites
maintained and/or operated by third parties (“Third Party Websites”). Mktg does not
endorse, and is not responsible for: (i) the Third Party Websites and the policies and
practices in connection with the Third Party Websites; or (ii) the products, services,
Surveys, and/or opportunities advertised, offered, and/or sold by, through or in
connection with the Third Party Websites. Mktg does not make any representations or
warranties regarding the Third Party Eebsites and any associated content. Please
carefully review all policies, and the terms and conditions, applicable to the Third Party
Websites and any associated content.
10. Agreement to Privacy Policy; Changes to Privacy Policy
By submitting your Personal Information to Mktg, you signify your acceptance of this
Privacy Policy. Mktg hereby reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy,
from time to time, and Mktg will post any such changes on Mktg's Website for your
review. Your continued use of, and interaction with, Mktg’s Surveys and this website,
after Mktg revises this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy,
as amended.
11. Agreement to Privacy Policy; Changes to Privacy Policy
In the event that you have any issues, concerns, or complaints, or would like additional
information about Mktg's privacy practices, please contact Mktg by regular mail,
postage pre-paid to:
Mktg, Inc.
200 Carleton Avenue
East Islip, NY 11730 USA

Attn: ?
[Do we want to include an email channel?]
Last Updated: June 1, 2013
Notes:
1. We’ll need to place a link to this Privacy Policy on website(s).
2. We’ll likely need to place a link to this Privacy Policy on the screens that ask for
Facebook ‘Likes.’
3. Once Mktg builds a panel, we’ll need to:
a. Place link to this Privacy Policy on survey invites
b. We’ll need to expand to speak to panelist access to Personal Information.
c. We’ll need to expand to address opt-out.
d. We’ll likely need to expand to address EU Safe Harbor Certification (if we get any
panel joins from the EU, etc.)
